Finding Aid to the Women's Project Theater records SSC.MS.00361
Sophia Smith Collection
Women's Project Theater records
1951-2010
Sophia Smith Collection
WP Theater (New York, N.Y.)
SSC.MS.00361
82 linear feet (98 containers)
Women's Project (WP) Theater was founded in 1978 by Julia Miles to develop and cultivate the creative talents of women in the American theater. WP Theater sought to give women from all areas of theater the opportunity to establish their professional crediblity, gain visibility and foster their artistic growth. The collection includes play scripts, promotional materials, administrative records, and materials related to Julia Miles, founder and artistic director. WP Theater often comissioned plays by women writers. Playwrights whose work WP Theater produced, either in public rehearsed readings or full productions, make up a significant portation of these records and include those by such widely recognized authors as Cynthia Ozick, Eve Ensler, Paula Giddings,Susan Brownmiller, Gail Sheehy, Judith Viorst, Molly Haskell and Penelope Gilliatt. Also included is a script for Letters Home by Rose Lerman Goldemberg based on Sylvia Plath's Letters Home.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for use without restriction beyond the standard terms and conditions of Smith College Special Collections.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Julia and Lisa Miles between 1989 and 2014.
Biographical / Historical
Women's Project (WP) Theater was founded in 1978 by Julia Miles to address the conspicuous underrepresentation of women artists working in American theater. Its purpose was to identify and nurture the work of women-identified playwrights, directors, and actors. It was previously known as The Women's Project, and Women's Project and Productions. The playwrights whose works were produced by WP theater, either in public rehearsed readings or full productions make up a significant portion of these records. They include scripts by include well-known authors including Joyce Carol Oates, Susan Brownmiller, Paula Giddings, Eve Ensler, Wendy Wasserstein, Gail Sheehy, Cynthia Ozick and Molly Haskell.
Under a grant from the Ford Foundation, Miles first created The Women's Project under the umbrella of The American Place Theatre to encourage the development of female playwrights and directors and to provide a forum for their work. For its first nine years, WP Theater staged its productions in the basement of the American Place Theatre and, while there, produced rehearsed readings, studio productions, and, in a few cases, main-stage productions. In 1987, the project left the American Place Theatre and became an independent organization.
Since 1978, WP Theater has produced more than 600 Off-Broadway plays and developmental projects and has partnered with a number of other New York theater companies for co-productions, including Playwrights Horizons and The New Group. Often, WP Theater produces plays that have New York or world premieres. The WP Theater expanded their reach to new audiences and participants by integrating programs such as rehearesd readings for plays in development, residencies, internships for cis, trans* and gender non-conforming playwrights and writing teams, guest workshops, and partnerships with other theater organizations.
Scope and Contents
The Women's Project (WP)Theater records include play scripts and materials related to play productions, as well as the administrative records of the theater. The scripts in the collection include those by such recognized writers as Cynthia Ozick, Eve Ensler, Paula Giddings, Susan Brownmiller, Gail Sheehy, Judith Viorst, Molly Haskell and Penelope Gilliatt. Also included is a script for Letters Home by Rose Lerman Goldemberg based on Sylvia Plath's letters to her family. Particularly well documented are the theater education program and plays commissioned by WP Theater. Records are divided into three series. Series I contains materials related to plays and productions put on by WP Theater. Included are draft, revised and final scripts; production materials; play development materials; information on rehearsed readings; cast contact lists and directories; advertising; information on directors, composers, and playwrights; costume designs; publicity materials; correspondence; and audiovisual materials such as audio tapes, photographs, VHS tapes, CDs, and slides. The series includes oversize posters, flyers, art work and costume designs. Information on festivals, play series, and plays put on in a particular season can be found in Series II.
Series II contains administrative records, including newsletters, budgets and financial materials, correspondence, board minutes, flyers, costume designs and information on festivals and series, as well as some art work. There are also notes and documents evaluating the quality of scripts that have been submitted by playwrights. Particularly well documented in this series is the WP Theater education program for New York high school students, Ten Centuries of Women Writers. Education materials include curriculum, correspondence, research, student work, and funding records.
Series III contains the personal records of Julia Miles, the founder and longtime artistic director of Women's Project Theater. Her papers include correspondence, information on her acting career, and information on other organizations she was involved with. Her activity in the Women's Forum, her founding of League of Professional Theatre Women, and her involvement with the Four Women Production Company are especially well documented.
Separated Materials
In February, 2019, duplicate ticket stubs from various performances, playbills, newsletters and scripts were removed from the collection and recycled. A few of each of these items were kept before removing the duplicates. Employee and student financial information was also removed and destroyed. Plays and playbills unrelated to Women's Project Theater were discarded.
Feminist theater; Women in the theater; American drama--Women authors--History and criticism; Women dramatists, American--20th century--Sources; Ross, Sharon; Miles, Julia; McNulty, Lisa
- SERIES I. Plays, 1963-2008; 55.333 linear feet (66 containers)
  Scope and Contents
  Series I includes play scripts and materials related to rehearsed reading and full productions of those scripts. The scripts in this collection include those by such recognized women writers as Cynthia Ozick, Eve Ensler, Paula Giddings, Susan Brownmiller, Gail Sheehy, Judith Viorst, Molly Haskell and Penelope Gilliatt. Also included is a script, Letters Home, by Rose Lerman Goldemberg, based on Sylvia Plath's letters to her family. Series I contains draft, revised and final scripts; production materials; play development materials; cast contact lists and directories; advertising; information on directors, composers, and playwrights; original costume designs; publicity materials; correspondence; and audiovisual materials such as audio tapes, photographs, VHS tapes, CDs, and slides. The series includes oversize posters, flyers, costue designs and other art work. Information on festivals, play series, and plays put on in a particular season can be found in Series II.
  Of particiular interest are notes and documents created during the script selection process, evaluating the quality of scripts submitted by playwrights found throughout.
  - 3 on a Train to Colgate by Pearl Cleage, script, undated (Box 1)
  - 11 Shades of White: The story of Veronica Lake by Sharon Houck Ross, scripts with notes, 1992-1994 (Box 1)
  - 111 Baron Road by Meredith Muncy, scripts with notes, 1990-1991 (Box 1)
  - 222 1/2 by Joan Vail Thorne scripts and rehearsed reading administrative materials, 1982-1991 (Box 1)
  - Sound recordings of 222 1/2 by Joan Vail Thorne, 1982; 2 items (2 audiocassettes) (Box 89)
  - 2000 Miles by Diana Son, script, 1993 (Box 1)
  - Abington Square by Maria Irene Fornes, script, production notebooks, playbills, reviews, 1985-1906 (Box 1)
  - The Absence of Miracles ad the Rise of the Middle Class by Lynne Alvarez, script, 1994 (Box 1)
  - Accelerando by Lisa Loomer, script, 1991-06 (Box 1)
  - accepting applause by Catherine Filloux, undated (Box 1)
  - Sound recordings of Acrobatics by Joyce Aaron, 1980; 2 items (Two audiocassettes) (Box 89)
  - African Interlude by Martie Evans Charles, script, 1978 (Box 1)
  - Afterbirth by Elaine Jackson, script, 1982 (Box 1)
  - After the Good War by Lavonne Mueller, script, contract, 1980 (Box 2)
  - After the Revolution by Nadja Tesich, script with notes, reviews, program, miscellaneous materials, 1977-1979 (Box 2)
  - The Agreement by Julianne Boyd, script, rehearsed readings list, 1984-1985 (Box 2)
  - Alabama Rain by Velina Hasu Houston, script with drafts, 1993 (Box 2)
  - Sound recording of Albinoni, 1 items (One audio reel-to-reel tape) (Box 97)
  - Alfred Jarry Loves Oscar Wilde by Dorothy Valesco, script, correspondence, miscellaneous materials, 1977-1979 (Box 2)
  - All Dressed Up and Nowhere to Go by Catherine Filloux, script, miscellaneous materials, 1994-1995 (Box 2)
  - All There Is by Lois Smith, revised script, 1983-06 (Box 2)
  - All These Blessings by June Jordan, draft script, 1988 (Box 2)
  - All Things Nice by Sharman MacDonald, script master copy, 1991-11-01 (Box 2)
  - Almost Asleep by Julie Herbert, script, undated (Box 2)
  - Almost Sisters by Lynda Sturmer, rehearsed reading script, 1998 (Box 2)
  - Al's Lunchette Stationers Drink Coca-Cola by Paul Cizmar, rehearsed reading script, 1984-1985 (Box 2)
  - Alternating Currents by Lisa L. Humbertson, rehearsed reading script, 1994-04-30 (Box 2)
  - An American in Me by Rebecca Gilman, script, 1999 (Box 2)
  - Amphibians by Molly Haskell, scripts with notes, programs, miscellaneous notes and other materials, 1991-1993 (Box 2)
  - A My Name is Alice conceived and directed by Joan Micklin Silver and Julianne Boyd, script, publicity, clippings, royalties lawsuit materials, 1983-1984 (Box 3)
  - Sound recording of A...My Name Will Always be Alice songs, 1996; 1 items (One CD) (Box 97)
  - Sound recording of A: Representation #1 Dub A, 1 items (1 audiocassette) (Box 96)
  - Sound recordings of My Name is Alice by Joan Micklin Silver and Julianne Boyd, Acts I, II, and live, 1983; 9 items (9 audiocassettes) (Box 89)
  - Anatomy of a Suicide by Kate Moira Ryan, script, 1993-06-02 (Box 3)
  - Ancient Echoes by Ms. M. a. Johnson, revised script, Tandem Acts flyer, 1986 (Box 3)
  - Ancient Lights by Shelagh Stephenson, script, contact sheet, 2000-2002 (Box 3)
  - Antigona Furiosa By Griselda Gambaro, script, 1988 (Box 3)
  - Any Place But Here by Caridad Suich, revised script, 1992-02-11 (Box 3)
  - The A 'PART' MENT by Mischael angel Johnson, script, 1986 (Box 3)
  - Apewatch by Elaine Osio, script, 1983-11-21 (Box 3)
  - Approximating Mother by Kathleen Tolan, script, publicity, programs, correspondence, reviews, miscellaneous materials, 1990-1992 (Box 3)
  - Artemisia by Tonya Bassett, script, correspondence, 1994-1996 (Box 4)
  - Arthur and Leila by Cherylene Lee, scripts with notes, 1992-1993 (Box 4)
  - The Assassination of Frederico Garcia Lorca by Lavonne Mueller, performance script, 1980-1989 (Box 4)
  - The Autobiography of Aiken Fiction by Kate Moira Ryan, script, publicity, program, notes and miscellaneous materials, 1992-1994 (Box 4)
  - Awake by Phyllis Nagy, master script, 1988-1994 (Box 4)
  - Sound recording of Backlash: The Cabaret, submissions, 1 items (One audiocassette) (Box 89)
  - Ballad Hunter by Jenny Laird, rehearsed reading script, 2001 (Box 4)
  - Sound recording of Bang Bang Uber Alles: A Musical Drama by June Jordan and Adrienne Torf, 1983-1984; 1 items (1 audiocassette) (Box 89)
  - Baptismal by Steve Tesich, script, unknown (Box 4)
  - Barnstormer by Cheryl L. Davis, rehearsed reading script, 2000 (Box 4)
  - Beach Daze by Sallie Bingham, script, undated (Box 4)
  - The Bear Facts by Jo Carson, scripts, 1991-1992 (Box 4)
  - Sound recordings of The Beautiful Lady by Elizabeth Swados, Acts I and II, 2 items (Two audiocassettes) (Box 89)
  - Behind Closed Doors by Clare Coss, script, 1982-1983 (Box 4)
  - Beside the Still Waters, 1983 (Box 4)
  - Best of Both Worlds publicity, reviews, program, student study guide, 2004 (Box 4)
  - The Big Lie by Joan Ross Sorkin, script, 1999 (Box 5)
  - The Big Window by Kate Browne, casting, correspondence, notes, scripts, miscellaneous materials, 1995-1996 (Box 5)
  - Sound recordings of The Big Window by Kate Browne, 1994-1996; 10 items (10 audiocassettes) (Box 89)
  - Billy and the Rainbow by Susan Lukas, script, manager's book, 1978-1979 (Box 5)
  - Sound recordings of Billy and the Rainbow by Susan Lukas, 2 items (2 audiocassettes) (Box 89)
  - Birdy by William Wharton, script, notes, correspondence, financial documents, miscellaneous materials, 2000-2003 (Box 5)
  - Black by Joyce Carol Oates, scripts, contracts, correspondence, publicity, reviews, study guide miscellaneous materials, 1993-1994 (Box 5, Box 6)
  - Blackbird by Joan Eades, script, 1985 (Box 6)
  - Black Burner Murder by Michele Aldin, draft script, 2002 (Box 6)
  - Black Novel With Argentines by Cirtella Ranieri, script, notes, prograam, 1994 (Box 6)
  - Blessings of Chairman Mao by Kitty Chen, reading script draft, 1998 (Box 6)
  - Blood Memory notes, correspondence, budget, miscellaneous materials, 1988-1989 (Box 6)
  - Blood of My Blood by Anne Garcia-Romero, 1992 (Box 6)
  - Boundary by Tammy Ryan, script, 1993 (Box 6)
  - Boy by Diana Son, rehearsed reading scripts, 1998 (Box 6)
  - Boys and Girls, Men and Women by Gina Wendkos, script, 1985-1986 (Box 6)
  - Bread by Margaret Hunt, script, Tandem Acts flyer, 1995 (Box 6)
  - Breaking the Prarie Wolf Code by Lavonne Mueller. script, poster, press releases, budget, contracts,, personnel and miscellaneous materials, 1995 (Box 6, Box 7)
    General
  - Broken Borders by Elizabeth Wray correspondence and miscellaneous materials, 1979 (Box 7)
  - Sound recordings of Broken Borders by Elizabeth Wray, 2 items (2 audiocassettes) (Box 89)
  - Broken Morning by Chiori Miyagawa script, contact sheet, 1999 (Box 7)
  - The Brooklyn Trojan Women by Carol Braverman, script, contact sheets, correspondence, 1990-1993 (Box 7)
  - The Brothers by Kathleen Collins, script, publicity, personnel and miscellaneous materials, 1980-1983 (Box 7)
  - Sound recordings of The Brothers by Kathleen Collins, 1981; 3 items (3 audiocassettes) (Box 90)
  - Burn Out: A History of the World Up in Smoke by Shelley Berc, script, 1984-1985 (Box 7)
  - Butterfly Kiss by Phyllis Nagy, script, 1988-1994 (Box 7)
  - but there are fires by Caridad Svich, scripts, 1989-1994 (Box 7)
  - By the Bog of Cats by Marina Carr, script, 1999 (Box 7)
  - Carson McCullers (Historically Inaccurate) by Sarah Schulman, script, program, contracts, publicity, miscellaneous materials, 2001-2002 (Box 7)
  - Cage Rhythm by Kia Corthron, 1993 (Box 7)
  - The Cataract by Lisa D'Amour publicity, clippings and student study guide, 2006 (Box 7)
  - Catch and Release by Carol Thompson Hemingway, script, 1983-1984 (Box 7)
  - Chain by Pearl Cleage, script, program, rehearsal notes, 1970-1992 (Box 8)
  - Cheat by Julie Jensen, script press, reviews, casting, budget, miscellansoue materials, 2001-2003 (Box 8)
  - The Chemistry of Change by Marlane Meyer, script, production information, program, contracts, miscellaneous materials, 1998-1999 (Box 8)
  - Sound recordings of Chemistry of Change by Marlane Meyer, 1999; 1 items (1 audiocassette) (Box 90)
  - Sound recordings of Chicanismo: Texas by Francisco Gonzalez, 1988; 1 items (1 audiocassette) (Box 90)
  - Chickenbone Beach by Jill Gorham, scripts, 1987-1989 (Box 8)
  - Clark in Sarajevo by Catherine Zimdahl, scrirpt, 1999 (Box 9)
  - Come Down Burning by Kia Corthron, first draft script, 1990 (Box 9)
  - Commercial Break by Leslie Glass, script, headshot, notes, miscellaneous material, 1982 (Box 9)
  - Sound recordings of Commercial Break by Leslie Glass, 1982; 2 items (2 audiocassettes) (Box 90)
  - Company Comin' by Delores Sutton, script, notes, miscellaneous material, 1995 (Box 9)
  - The Confessions of Many Strangers by L. Mueller, script, notes, miscellaneous materials, 1994-1995 (Box 9)
  - Consequence by Kat Smith, script, budgets, personnel, publicity, program, miscellaneous materials, 1986-1987 (Box 9)
  - Sound recordings of Consequence by Kat Smith, sound effects, 1987; 21 items (21 audiocassettes); 2 items (Two 71/2 IPS 2 Track Mono Sound Tapes) (Box 91)
  - Constance and the Musician by Caroline Kava, publicity, program, press, budgets, contracts, miscellaneous material (Box 9)
  - Converting by Catherine Filloux, script, 1995 (Box 9)
  - Cookie Jar by Pat Kaufman, script, 1984 (Box 9)
  - The Corridor by Diane Kagan, script, correspondence, miscellaneous materials, 1979 (Box 9)
  - Couvade by Sallie Bingham, script, undated (Box 9)
  - Cousins by Anna Deveare Smith, script, miscellaneous material, 1975-1982 (Box 9)
  - Sound recordings of Cousins by Anna Deveare Smith, 1982; 1 items (1 audiocassette) (Box 90)
  - Cradle Song by Mary Bracken Phillips, script, 1982 (Box 10)
  - The Crawlin' Space by Susan Flakes, scripts, 1988-1990 (Box 10)
  - Crocodiles in the Potomac by Wendy Belden, scripts, budget, box office reports, press, casting, schedules, miscellaneous materials, 1995 (Box 10)
  - Crooked by Catherine Trieschmann, publicity, reviews, 2008 (Box 10)
  - Crossing to Gethesmane by Kerry Kennedy, script, 1989 (Box 10)
  - Crowning Glories by Sandra Torres, undated (Box 10)
  - Sound recordings of Cuatro Milpas by Francisco Gonzalez, 1988; 1 items (1 audiocassette) (Box 90)
  - Cut the Ribbons musical review, script, 1989 (Box 10)
  - D. Boone by Marsha Norman, script, 1992-1993 (Box 10)
  - Damage and Desire by Kate Moira Ryan, scripts, 1994 (Box 10)
  - Dancing in the Dark by Sallie Bingham, script, 1983-1984 (Box 10)
  - Sound recordings of Dancing in the Dark by Sallie Bingham, 3 items (3 audiocassettes) (Box 90)
  - The Danube by Maria Irene Fornes, script, 1983-1984 (Box 10)
  - The Darkness and the Light by Sallie Bingham, scripts, 1986-1987 (Box 10)
  - Dawn's Early Light by Billie Allen, scripts, 1983 (Box 11)
  - Daytrips by Jo Carson, scripts rehearsal/performance reports, publicity, program, reviews, miscellaneous materials, 1988-1989 (Box 11)
  - Sound recording of Day Trips, 1990; 2 items (Two audio reel-to-reel tape) (Box 97)
  - Sound recordings of Daytrips by Jo Carson, 1990; 2 items (2 audiocassettes) (Box 90)
  - Death of a Miner by Paula Cizmar, contracts, publicity, press, miscellaneous materials, 1981-1982 (Box 11)
  - Sound recordings of Death of a Miner by Paula Cizmar, 1981; 2 items (2 audiocassettes) (Box 90)
  - The Death of Henry Flagler by Sally Bingham, script, notrs, miscellaneous materials, 1995 (Box 11)
  - The Death of the last Black Man in the Whole Entire World by Suzan-Lori Parks, 1989 (Box 11)
  - Defying Gravity by Jane Anderson, scripts, 1987-1991 (Box 11)
  - The Depot by Eve Ensler, script, 1985-1986 (Box 12)
  - Desdemona by Paula Vogel, script, 1986 (Box 12)
  - The Desert by Janet Neipris, correspondence, miscellaneous materials, 1986 (Box 12)
  - Sound recordings of The Desert by Janet Neipris, 1980; 2 items (2 audiocassettes) (Box 90)
  - The Devil Dances by Reza de Wet, scripts, 1989 (Box 12)
  - Dinosaurs by Gina Wendkos, script, 1987 (Box 12)
  - The Divine Feast by Lisa D'Amour, script, 2000 (Box 12)
  - The Disturbed Mojave Pattern by Adelaide Mac Kenzie, script, 1991 (Box 12)
  - The Dizziness of Too Many Possibilities, script, 1980-1989 (Box 12)
  - Domino Six by Laura Quinn, script, 1991 (Box 12)
  - Sound recordings of Do Women Want by unknown author, 2 items (2 audiocassettes) (Box 90)
  - The Dream by Michael angel Johnson, scripts with notes, 1993 (Box 12)
  - Dream House by Darrah Cloud, script, 1996 (Box 12)
  - Dream of Common Language by Heather McDonald, script, notes, program, correspondence, study guide and miscellaneous materials, 1990-1992 (Box 12, Box 13)
  - Drop Everything by Phyllis Purscell, scripts, 1990 (Box 13)
  - Duets by Phyllis Purscell, script, correspondence, miscellaneous materials, 1981 (Box 13)
  - Sound recordings of Duets by Phyllis Purscell, 1981; 2 items (2 audiocassettes) (Box 90)
  - The Early Girl by Carolibne Kava, script, 1983 (Box 13)
  - Eating Chicken Feet by Kitty Chen, script, program, marketing, sales, contracts, miscellaneous materials, 1993-1994 (Box 13, Box 14)
  - Effie's Burning by Valerie Windsor, script, 1993 (Box 14)
  - Sound recording of Emma Millie Cues, 1 items (One audio reel-to-reel tape) (Box 97)
  - Encanto Fire by Rosa Lowinger, script, contracts, programs, publicity, reviews, miscellaneous materials, 1990-1991 (Box 14)
  - Enchantment by Carson Kreitzer, student study guide, undated (Box 14)
  - Entry Points by Sharon Houck Ross, scripts, noytes, miscellaneous material, 1990 (Box 14)
  - The Eric Clapton Breakfast Club by Taylor Sarton, script, 1993 (Box 14)
  - Essex Girls by Rebecca Prichard, script, 1994 (Box 14)
  - Etta Jenks by Marlene Meyer, script, contracts, correspondence, program, prop list, press, miscellaneous materials, 1986-1988 (Box 14)
  - Eurydice by Sarah Ruhl, script, 2002 (Box 14)
  - Even Among These Rocks by Claire Chafee, script, 1988-1994 (Box 15)
  - Everything That Rises Must Converge by Joan Vail Thorne, 1991 (Box 15)
  - The Exact Center of the Universe by Joan Vail Thorne, scripts, contracts, casting, budget, press, miscellaneous materials, 1997-1998 (Box 15)
  - The Existential Gourmet by Bruce Ostler, script, 2000 (Box 15)
  - Eyes of the Heart by Catherine Filloux, script, 1998 (Box 15)
  - Faces: a Living Newspaper on Aides by Carolyn Anderson and Wilma Hall, script, clippings, miscellaneous materials, 1990 (Box 16)
  - Farley and Betsy by Daisy Foote, script, 1999 (Box 16)
  - Fastia by Diane Ney, script, correspondence, miscellaneous material, 1993-1994 (Box 16)
  - Father Dreams by Mary Gallagher, correspondence, miscellaneous material, 1980 (Box 16)
  - Sound recordings of Film Demo by Noa Ain, 1997-1998; 2 items (2 audiocassettes) (Box 90)
  - Finding Claire by Kim Merrill, script, 2001 (Box 16)
  - The Fine Things in Life by Lydia Stryk, scripts, notes, miscellaneous materials, 1993-1994 (Box 16)
  - Fiona's Mane by Jane Shepard, script, flyer, 1996 (Box 16)
  - Fire by Bryna Wortman, script, 1983 (Box 16)
  - Fire and Ice by Cate Ryan, script, 1992 (Box 16)
  - Fire in the Future by J.M. Schenkar, script, 1988 (Box 16)
  - Flappers by Annie Evans, scripts, 1995 (Box 16)
  - Flesh and Blood by Edna O'Brien, scripts, 1988-1989 (Box 16)
  - Flesh of My Flesh by Cassandra Medley, draft script, flyer, 1995 (Box 16)
  - Flooding by Sharon Houck Ross, script, notes, program, 1995 (Box 16)
  - Flood by Sallie Bingham, script, 1988-1994 (Box 16)
  - Flowers and Household Goods by Momoko Iko, script, notes, correspondence, miscellaneous material, 1979-1980 (Box 17)
  - Sound recordings of Flowers and Household Goods by Momoko Iko, 3 items (3 audiocassettes) (Box 90)
  - Flyin' West by Pearl Cleage, script, 1988-1994 (Box 17)
  - Forgivable by Tracy Thorne, script, 1997 (Box 17)
  - The Forgotten Lover by Susan Dworkin, scripts, 1991-1992 (Box 17)
  - Four Corners by Gina Wendcos and Donna Bond, rehearsal schedule, correspondence, budget, posters and miscellaneous materials, 1984-1985 (Box 17, Box 98)
  - Sound recording of Four Corners master tapes, 2 items (Two audio reel-to-reel tapes) (Box 97)
  - Free China by Brighde Mullins, script, 1988-1994 (Box 17)
  - Free Fall by Laura Harrington, scripts, 1982-1985 (Box 17)
  - Frida by Hillary Blecher, scripts, notes, budgets, piublicity, programs, contracts, miscellaneous materials, 1991-1992 (Box 17)
  - From a Small Room by Carol K. Mack, script, 1985 (Box 18)